CHRIS SCHMITZ

San Antonio, TX

https://www.linkedin.com/in/Chris-J-Schmitz

815-922-8895



Software Engineering Student dedicated to improving skills through hands-on learning and development work. With work experience in Technical Support and Operational Management. Personal and school projects: web based projects in HTML/CSS/JavaScript as well as desktop applications in Java. Well-organized and collaborative team player with strong communication and analytical abilities. Looking forward to continue learning about the software development lifecycle and producing clean code.



Skills

- Network troubleshooting, Desktop and Application Support
- Operations and Project Management
- Ticket support system management
- Programming knowledge in : Java, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Data analysis



Work History

2021-08 - Current

OPERATIONS TEAM MANAGER

IBEX Global, San Antonio, Texas

- Implemented process improvement to shape organizational culture, optimize procedures for higher efficiency and help company evolve and grow.
- Reduced process bottlenecks by training and coaching employees on practices, procedures and performance strategies.
- Kept detailed records of daily progress to identify and correct areas needing improvement.
- Resolved staff member conflicts, actively listening to concerns and finding appropriate middle ground.
- Worked with IT department to address technology issues and shortfalls.

SENIOR LEVEL TECHNICAL SUPPORT REPRESENTATIVE

IBEX Global, San Antonio, Texas

 Worked with software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released software and assisted in deployment of release fixes.

2020-08 - 2021-07

 Resolved diverse range of technical issues across multiple systems and applications for customers and end-users across various time zones.

- Managed over 40 Customer calls per day. Performing in the top 5% of the department.
- Assisted with updating technical support best practices for use by team.
- Managed high levels of call flow and responded to IOS and MacOS technical support needs.
- Collaborated with supervisors to escalate and address customer inquiries or technical issues.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors.

Delivery and Logistics

Menards, Bradley, IL

- Used customer service skills to help guests locate and load products, as well as answered any questions guests had about our products.
- Organized purchase and delivery of materials needed for various contracts.
- Handled between 10-20 deliveries per day.
- Collaborated with shipping department staff to facilitate smooth materials returns to correct vendors.
- Generated documentation and information required for customer shipments.
- Maintained excellent working relationships with customers by efficiently responding to inquiries and complaints concerning work orders, invoices and shipments.



Education

Bachelor of Science: COMPUTER SCIENCE

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY - Remote

2016-03 - 2020-05

2020-05 - Current